Joel José Herranz Bustamante

Full Stack Developer

EMAIL joel.herranz@gmail.com **TEL** +33 7 52 44 22 75

WEB https://herranz.onrender.com REPO https://github.com/j-herranz **REGION** Île-de-France **DRIVER'S LICENCE** B, car available

With two years of experience, I have led three solutions from their design to their deployment and have completed several personal projects using React and Node.js. I have strong skills in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, PHP, Git/GitHub, SQL, and PL/SQL, as well as a proven ability to transform user needs into effective web solutions. Always eager to learn, I quickly adapt to new technologies and challenges.

Skills

Hard Skills

- Front-end Development: JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS.
- Asynchronous requests: AJAX (XHR, Fetch, async/await).
- Back-end Development: Node.js, Express.js, and PHP.
- Database Management: MySQL, SQL, and PL/SQL.

Project Management

- Requirements analysis.
- Creation of specifications documents.

Soft Skills

- Agile Methodology.
- Collaborative work.

- API Design and Development.
- Version Control: Git and GitHub.
- Advanced Algorithms.
- Object-Oriented Programming: C#, Java.
- Evolutionary and corrective maintenance of applications.
- Writing of technical (UML) and functional specifications.
- Continuous technological monitoring.
- Initiative and proactivity.

Professional Experiences

2023 – 2024 (10 months) Fixed-term contract in Full-Stack Web Development (Tremblay-en-France - Riccobono)

Design and creation of two web applications (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL and PL/SQL), one of which is connected to an existing desktop application (ODBC protocol).

2022 – 2023 (12 months) **Apprenticeship in Full-Stack Web Development** (Tremblay-en-France - Riccobono) Design and creation of a desktop application for network architecture inventory (WinDev).

2022 (3 months) Internship in Full-Stack Web Development (Le Chesnay – Lycée Blanche de Castille) Design and creation of a web application for student tracking with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, PL/SQL and Bootstrap.

2018-2021 (36 months) Statistical Research Engineer (Paris, INSERM)

Survey coordination, statistical data analysis, and dissemination of results. Use of SAS, R and SQL language.

Education

2022-2023	Bachelor's Degree in Internet Programming and Mobile Systems, Université Paris-Saclay Supervised Projects: - Creation of two dynamic websites (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React and Node.js) Mobile app development using Android Studio (Java) and Xcode (Swift).
2021-2022	Technical Degree in Computer Science (1 year special program), Université Paris-Saclay
2015-2016	Master's Degree in Population Dynamics, Institut de Démographie de l'Université Paris 1 Demographic analysis, applied statistics, SAS programming, cohort tracking, spatial analysis.

Language Skills

Spanish	Native.
English	C1 Level, 945/990 points (Test of English for International Communication TOEIC - 2022).
French	C1 Level (TCF – Institut Français de Madrid – 2015)